=Recruit A General to lead the Troops=
=Ambil Seorang Jeneral untuk mengetuai Pasukan=
=Episode 19=
=Episode 19=
Li Chengyu.
Li Chengyu.
These people are here to save you.
These people are here to save you.
And none of them will get away with it!
And none of them will get away with it!
Let's get started.
Let's get started.
(Order)
(Pesanan)
Execute him!
bunuh dia!
(Huaikang Gate)
(Huaikang Gate)
Stop! Stop it!
Stop! Stop it!
Here comes His Majesty's decree!
Here comes His Majesty's decree!
Hyah!
Hyah!
"As the General God of War, Li Chengyu
"As the General God of War, Li Chengyu
has concealed his identity
has concealed his identity
for a secret operation
for a secret operation
on my command.
on my command.
Today marks the end of the operation.
Today marks the end of the operation.
The Sword of God of War shall be returned to him
The Sword of God of War shall be returned to him
and his true identity
and his true identity
shall be reinstated."
shall be reinstated."
Release the arrow! Shoot!
Release the arrow! Shoot!
(Huaikang Gate)
(Huaikang Gate)
Cold Tiger!
Harimau Sejuk!
Retreat!
Retreat!
Chengyu.
Chengyu.
You took that arrow for me.
You took that arrow for me.
Now I've taken all these arrows for you.
Now I've taken all these arrows for you.
Well, Chengyu,
Well, Chengyu,
you forbid me to cry,
you forbid me to cry,
so I'm not going to cry now.
so I'm not going to cry now.
I don't fear death.
I don't fear death.
So don't cry, Chengyu.
So don't cry, Chengyu.
It turns out you're a general.
It turns out you're a general.
No wonder I always found you brilliant.
No wonder I always found you brilliant.
I'm proud
I'm proud
to have a general
to have a general
as my brother.
as my brother.
I'm taking you to the capital, so you can be an official.
I'm taking you to the capital, so you can be an official.
I can't wait until then.
I can't wait until then.
Cold Tiger!
Harimau Sejuk!
I don't care.
I don't care.
I'm going to stay at Qingfeng Stronghold.
I'm going to stay at Qingfeng Stronghold.
It is my home,
It is my home,
and you are my brother.
and you are my brother.
Bark!
Bark!
Woof!
Woof!
Well,
Baiklah,
Chengyu,
Chengyu,
aren't you going to let me tag along?
aren't you going to let me tag along?
I'll come again when I'm free.
I'll come again when I'm free.
The Sword of God of War
The Sword of God of War
slays warlords
slays warlords
and eradicates traitors.
and eradicates traitors.
(General.)
(General.)
(Hand over evidence of the Chancellor's rebellion)
(Hand over evidence of the Chancellor's rebellion)
(and Chen Xinrou shall be captured.)
(and Chen Xinrou shall be captured.)
What's with all those bones, Cold Tiger?
What's with all those bones, Cold Tiger?
It's an honor.
It's an honor.
Since you own many, let me have one of them.
Since you own many, let me have one of them.
I can't simply do that.
I can't simply do that.
Here.
Di sini.
I've been wearing this for years,
I've been wearing this for years,
so it's got my smell.
so it's got my smell.
How was it?
How was it?
The body has been buried.
The body has been buried.
Cold Tiger was sloven.
Cold Tiger was sloven.
So make sure his tomb looks nice.
So make sure his tomb looks nice.
Yes, sir.
Ya, tuan.
Go on.
Teruskan.
Are you all right, General?
Are you all right, General?
What's the matter?
What's the matter?
His Majesty sent me here
His Majesty sent me here
to help you out.
to help you out.
After Minister Li Aotian took over,
After Minister Li Aotian took over,
I returned to the palace.
I returned to the palace.
Has Minister Li been away all this time?
Has Minister Li been away all this time?
Why are you in this state?
Why are you in this state?
Li Aotian?
Li Aotian?
Chengyu.
Chengyu.
Chengyu!
Chengyu!
Are you all right?
Are you all right?
What's happened?
What's happened?
Why are you injured?
Why are you injured?
Minister Li, why are you...
Minister Li, why are you...
It's a long story.
It's a long story.
His Majesty ordered me to come and help Chengyu.
His Majesty ordered me to come and help Chengyu.
But it's been a tough journey.
But it's been a tough journey.
Upon my arrival in the city, I learned about Chengyu's injury.
Upon my arrival in the city, I learned about Chengyu's injury.
That's why I rushed here.
That's why I rushed here.
Are you all right, Chengyu?
Are you all right, Chengyu?
Aotian.
Aotian.
What's exactly going on here?
What's exactly going on here?
I managed to have an audience with His Majesty in the capital.
I managed to have an audience with His Majesty in the capital.
He wanted me to come and help you.
He wanted me to come and help you.
After all, we're brothers.
After all, we're brothers.
Yet I ran into some problems on my way here.
Yet I ran into some problems on my way here.
I ended up having a fight in the woods
I ended up having a fight in the woods
and getting injured.
and getting injured.
Thus, the delay.
Thus, the delay.
Come to think of it,
Come to think of it,
perhaps the Chancellor purposely did that
perhaps the Chancellor purposely did that
to stop us from seeing each other.
to stop us from seeing each other.
Then what's with the evidence that was sent back to the palace?
Then what's with the evidence that was sent back to the palace?
Why did the Chancellor end up getting convicted?
Why did the Chancellor end up getting convicted?
I have no idea.
I have no idea.
Weren't you the one who investigated it?
Bukankah anda yang menyiasatnya?
Anyway, congratulations on your achievement.
Apapun, tahniah atas pencapaian anda.
No way.
tak boleh.
I must take Xinrou back to the capital and clear things up.
Saya mesti membawa Xinrou kembali ke ibu kota dan menyelesaikannya.
I'll come with you.
Saya akan ikut awak.
Aotian!
Aotian!
Looks like I've run out of strength.
Nampaknya aku sudah kehabisan tenaga.
I always end up holding you back, Chengyu.
Saya selalu menahan awak, Chengyu.
I'm sorry.
saya minta maaf.
Forget it.
Lupakan saja.
Too much has happened today.
Terlalu banyak yang berlaku hari ini.
You should get some rest.
Awak patut berehat.
Guard.
Pengawal.
Help Minister Li back to his quarters.
Bantu Menteri Li kembali ke rumahnya.
Please spare me, General!
Tolong selamatkan saya, Jeneral!
Who is the mastermind?
Siapa dalangnya?
Speak!
Cakap!
I don't know.
saya tak tahu.
I really don't know.
Saya benar-benar tidak tahu.
How smart of you.
Betapa bijaknya awak.
You know keeping quiet won't get you killed.
Anda tahu berdiam diri tidak akan membunuh anda.
Keep an eye on him!
Pantau dia!
Please spare me, General!
Tolong selamatkan saya, Jeneral!
(County Office)
(Pejabat Daerah)
(Come to think of it,)
(Coba fikirkan,)
(perhaps the Chancellor purposely did that)
(mungkin Canselor sengaja melakukan itu)
(to stop us from seeing each other.)
(untuk menghalang kita daripada melihat satu sama lain.)
(But the evidence submitted clearly showed the Chancellor was innocent.)
(Tetapi bukti yang dikemukakan jelas menunjukkan Canselor tidak bersalah.)
(As long as it was him,)
(Selagi itu dia,)
(the truth didn't matter.)
(kebenaran tidak penting.)
(Could it be him?)
(Mungkinkah dia?)
What are you doing?
awak buat apa?
I'm here to kill you!
Saya di sini untuk membunuh awak!
Have you lost your mind?
Adakah anda sudah hilang akal?
You got our leader thrown in jail.
Anda telah melemparkan pemimpin kami ke dalam penjara.
You tricked us!
Awak tipu kami!
I can't explain everything right now.
Saya tidak dapat menjelaskan semuanya sekarang.
But you have to trust me.
Tapi awak kena percaya saya.
I never meant to harm Xinrou. On the contrary, I'm trying to save her.
Saya tidak pernah berniat untuk membahayakan Xinrou. Sebaliknya, saya cuba menyelamatkannya.
Then what are you waiting for?
Jadi apa tunggu lagi?
Xinrou is the Chancellor's daughter.
Xinrou ialah anak perempuan Canselor.
She's been jailed for treason.
Dia telah dipenjarakan kerana khianat.
If I break her out now,
Jika saya putuskan dia sekarang,
it'll only show she's guilty.
ia hanya akan menunjukkan dia bersalah.
Tomorrow, I'll take her back to the capital
Esok, saya akan bawa dia balik ke ibu kota
and testify for her.
dan bersaksi untuknya.
I'll let you visit her,
Saya akan benarkan anda melawatnya,
so you'll know she's safe.
jadi anda akan tahu dia selamat.
Leader!
Pemimpin!
Xinrou!
Xinrou!
Minmin.
Minmin.
You must've been starving for days.
Mesti awak kelaparan berhari-hari.
Here, I made you your favorite pastries.
Di sini, saya membuatkan anda pastri kegemaran anda.
Sit down and try some.
Duduk dan cuba sedikit.
I'm tired of this flavor.
Saya bosan dengan perisa ini.
Make me something new after this.
Jadikan saya sesuatu yang baru selepas ini.
Xinrou.
Xinrou.
Are you...
adakah awak...
Here's some incense.
Berikut adalah beberapa kemenyan.
It drives away insects.
Ia menghalau serangga.
Take it, Xinrou.
Ambillah, Xinrou.
I'm not afraid of bugs.
Saya tidak takut pepijat.
I even catch them for medicine.
Saya juga menangkap mereka untuk ubat.
Got it?
faham?
By the way, Xinrou,
Ngomong-ngomong, Xinrou,
they say you're the Chancellor's daughter
mereka kata awak anak Canselor
and tied to the treason case.
dan terikat dengan kes khianat.
Is that true?
Adakah itu benar?
I don't know either.
saya pun tak tahu.
Years ago, I fell into the river and lost my memory.
Beberapa tahun lalu, saya jatuh ke dalam sungai dan hilang ingatan.
When I came around, I was already at the Shihou Stronghold.
Apabila saya datang, saya sudah berada di Kubu Kubu Shihou.
Maybe I really am the Chancellor's daughter.
Mungkin saya benar-benar anak Canselor.
Oh, right, where's Manyue?
Oh, betul, di mana Manyue?
Minister Li.
Menteri Li.
Who are you?
siapa awak
Have you really forgotten me?
Adakah anda benar-benar melupakan saya?
I know your whole family was wronged.
Saya tahu seluruh keluarga awak telah dianiaya.
I can get you out of here,
Saya boleh bawa awak keluar dari sini,
but you must work for me.
tetapi anda mesti bekerja untuk saya.
So it was you.
Jadi awak.
I knew you'd remember me.
Saya tahu awak akan ingat saya.
You saved me from this very prison
Awak selamatkan saya dari penjara ini
and had someone tattoo this mark then.
dan mempunyai seseorang tatu tanda ini kemudian.
You then sent me to Qingfeng Stronghold
Anda kemudian menghantar saya ke Kubu Qingfeng
to be your messenger.
untuk menjadi utusan anda.
Though we only met once,
Walaupun kita hanya bertemu sekali,
I will never forget
Saya tidak akan lupa
your kindness.
kebaikan awak.
Miss.
Cik.
It's a cold and damp night.
Ia adalah malam yang sejuk dan lembap.
You wouldn't want to catch a chill.
Anda tidak akan mahu berasa sejuk.
I was only carrying out His Majesty's orders.
Saya hanya melaksanakan titah Baginda.
By the way,
By the way,
did you help Chengyu at Qingfeng Stronghold?
adakah anda membantu Chengyu di Kubu Qingfeng?
I feel ashamed.
Saya berasa malu.
Aside from delivering messages,
Selain menyampaikan mesej,
I couldn't help him much.
Saya tidak dapat membantunya banyak.
May I ask if Chen Xinrou really took part in the rebellion?
Bolehkah saya bertanya sama ada Chen Xinrou benar-benar mengambil bahagian dalam pemberontakan?
Minister Li.
Menteri Li.
Your cough has gotten worse.
Batuk anda semakin teruk.
I'll search for the best physician to cure you.
Saya akan mencari doktor yang terbaik untuk menyembuhkan anda.
She hasn't sent word since she left for the capital.
Dia tidak menghantar khabar sejak dia pergi ke ibu kota.
We've sent her a letter.
Kami telah menghantar surat kepadanya.
Let's hope she's safe and sound.
Semoga dia selamat dan sihat.
Protect yourself.
Lindungi diri anda.
But this thing ensures your safety.
Tetapi perkara ini memastikan keselamatan anda.
Put it on.
Pakai.
Where's Li Chengyu?
Mana Li Chengyu?
He...
Dia...
Reporting!
Melaporkan!
General.
Umum.
Sir.
Tuan.
Chen Xinrou has poisoned the jailer.
Chen Xinrou telah meracuni penjaga penjara.
She said she'd kill the jailer unless she sees you, General.
Dia berkata dia akan membunuh penjaga penjara melainkan dia melihat kamu, Jeneral.
What?
apa?
♪If you've never seen a bloom, you can't know hope♪
???Jika anda tidak pernah melihat bunga, anda tidak boleh tahu harapan???
♪If you weren't here, I wouldn't have come♪
???Kalau awak tak ada, saya takkan datang???
♪On a soda-lit night, only the wind knows my love♪
???Pada malam bercahaya soda, hanya angin yang tahu cintaku???
♪It's a helpless kind of feeling♪
???Perasaan macam tak berdaya???
♪Like a feather of morning love falling into the deep sea♪
???Seperti bulu cinta pagi yang jatuh ke laut dalam???
♪Being unnoticed, yet I still tell you I love you♪
???Sebab tanpa disedari, namun saya masih memberitahu awak saya sayang awak???
♪But my confession is drowned out by the wind♪
???Tetapi pengakuan saya ditenggelamkan oleh angin???
♪You can't hear it♪
???Anda tidak boleh mendengarnya???
♪I also want to rush forward♪
???Saya juga mahu tergesa-gesa ke hadapan???
♪To give you all my heart♪
???Untuk memberikan anda semua hati saya???
♪Yet it's pushed away by you♪
???Namun ia ditolak oleh anda???
♪Whether love is spoken or left unspoken♪
???Sama ada cinta terucap atau dibiarkan tak terucap???
♪I know you understand♪
???Saya tahu awak faham???
♪It's just an accident♪
???Ia hanya kemalangan???
♪You longed to wander once more, by my side through the throng♪
???Anda ingin merayau sekali lagi, di sisi saya melalui kerumunan???
♪I know you weren't really here for me♪
???Saya tahu awak bukan di sini untuk saya???
♪Yet still, who else could bring a surprise quite like you♪
???Namun, siapa lagi yang boleh membawa kejutan seperti anda???
♪After you left, I didn't want to let go♪
???Selepas awak pergi, saya tak nak lepaskan???
♪You brushed past me, leaving your trace in the crowd♪
???Anda menepis saya, meninggalkan jejak anda di khalayak ramai???
♪I didn't shut you out♪
???Saya tak tutup mulut awak???
♪But I couldn't wait for you to stop♪
???Tetapi saya tidak sabar untuk anda berhenti???
♪Yet I seem to clutch you, unable to let you fade into the crowd♪
???Namun saya seolah-olah mencengkam anda, tidak dapat membiarkan anda memudar di hadapan orang ramai???